ı	Programming	Technical	Interpersonal	Tools	Techniques
Key Skills	R	Requirements Analysis	Team Management	Basic OpenCV	Topic Modelling
	Basic C++	Business Context &	reei	R-HBase	Sentiment Mining
	Basic Java I	Problem Definition	Counselling 1	PERT	Support Vector Machines

Senior Research Analyst, Innovation Labs

September 2012 - Present 1 year 6 months

Mu Sigma Business Solutions

Talent Quest

My work in Mu Sigma involves Analytics Research and Product Design, and is focused at information retrieval and visualization from large volume unstructured sources like twitter, text response surveys, resume databases etc. I use algos like Deep Learning, LDA, SVMs etc and tools like HBase to store and extract meaningful information from text, audio and image data. I am the primary developer in a team working on a product on automating enterprise scale unstructured data analysis.

I also work in the field of Computer Vision and the Internet of things, with focus on real time algorithms for seamless Man-Machine and Machine-2-Machine interactions. I lead a team of three people working towards creating product prototypes in the field.

Research Associate, Recruitments Consulting

June 2012 - August 2012 3 months

My work in Talent Quest involved Executive Search and Consulting Services to companies for various profiles, in mid- and senior management positions. I worked across domains and groups including The Oberoi Group and The Marriott Group in Hospitality, Towers-Watson in BFSI, Max Ventures, CVENT India and Rhythm Corner Associates.

Internships

Work Experience

Trainee Requitement Analyst

May 2011 - December 2011

TechEpsilon Software 8 months

Statistical Quality Assurance Intern

January 2012 - April 2012

Perfetti Van Melle India

4 months

Industrial Research Trainee December 2009

Ranbaxy Research Labs 1 month

Education

Bachelor of Engineering - Biotechnology

August 2008 - May 2012

Manipal Institute of Technology

4 years

AICCCE 2000

AISSCE 2008 April 2008

Delhi Public School, Vasant Kunj, New Delhi

Eeshan Chatterjee | Citizenship: Indian | Date of Birth: August 9, 1990

Eeshan Chatterjee eeshanchatterjee@gmail.com

9008419776

Projects

Deep Learning

January 2014

Used Stanford-CoreNLP based architectures to create sentiment mining engine in R, including sentence parse trees tagging and semantic compositionality analysis.

Historical Analysis on Tweets

Created the HBase schemas, rowkey designs, multicore processing paradigms to implement Topic Modelling and Sentiment Analysis for medium to large datasets of 20000+ tweets. Worked with MongoDB, Thrift Server and the RHbase package by Revolution Analytics.

Text Mining: Sentiment Analysis (Unsupervised Learning)

April 2013

Maintained a lexicon based sentiment scoring app + package for quasi real time and batch applications.

Text Mining: Sentiment Analysis (Supervised Learning)

March 2013

Implemented automated tagging for train data and an SVM based sentiment scoring (multi-class classification) in real time on streaming tweets.

Text Mining: Topic Modelling of Tweets

January 2013

Implemented LDA on tweets in a quasi real time fashion along with downstream analysis such as word and tweet associations.

Text Preprocessing/Cleanup

November 2012

Created reusable text cleanup module (R Package) for general cleanup tasks required as a precursor for most text mining applications.

Customer Feedback Analysis

March 2014

Mu Sigma Business Solutions

Primary Developer

Created a custom realtime customer feedback analysis product for the world's largest retailer achieveing huge reduction in issue identification and resolution time.

Transport Routes Optimization & Management

September 2013

Mu Sigma Business Solutions

Self- Internal Hackathon

Conceptualized, designed and created an app/productlet to optimize last-mile delivery routing with the aim to automate and optimize cab routing system based on ad-hoc requests. The app is extensible to optimize any local (intra-city) routing problem with constraints on number of vehicles, capacity of each vehicle, time, and distance amongst others.

HR Analytics- Employee Feedback Analysis

March 2013

Mu Sigma Business Solutions

Primary Developer

Conceptualized and created backend for a company wide automated employee feedback analysis application with metrics measuring sentiments, team cohesion, and quantified employee-manager relationships.

Office Automation System

April 2011

TechEpsilon Software

Requirement Analyst

Requirement Analysis, preparation of external requirement specifications document, and UI design for a software project for an international client.

Products